There's a new prompting technique for
Claude that's been blowing people's
minds over the past week. Because in a
single prompt, it can build fully
playable games and hyper custom 3D
worlds like these that even Karpati says
might be the future of prompting LLMs.
So today, I'll share with you this
technique called the gauntlet loop,
which might just be the quickest way for
you to learn how to fan out sub agents
to do work for you, so that even if
you're not into game development, you
can add this tool to your arsenal and
instantly get better at agentic AI. And
by the end, I'll share with you a skill
that lets you fully take advantage
[music] of this technique in the easiest
way possible. And if you're new, my name
is Jay. I spent over a decade working
with brands you may know, have been in
AI since my masters in data science. Now
I'm running an AI business and one of
the largest AI communities globally.
Let's dive into it. [music]
So, I first saw this prompting technique
from Matt Schumer who posted this insane
demo over at X where it already garnered
something like 4.8 million views. And he
says here that Claude Opus 5 oneshotted
this entire game with everything you see
in the demo being custom code without
any single external asset. And if Matt's
name is familiar and if you're in the AI
space for a while, that might be because
he actually wrote this article called
something big is happening which a lot
of people read a few months ago now
sitting at 87 million views. Point being
that he has been working with AI for
quite a while already and is actually a
good source from prompting techniques
like these. And if you see a claim like
this where an AI model supposedly
oneshots a game that looks as good as
this, complete with sound. By the way,
I'm not sure if you can hear that if I
just turn on the sound. Usually with
this, your first reaction would be a bit
skeptical if it was even made by AI,
which is quite understandable because
really the level of graphics here is
already quite extraordinary. But a few
days ago, Matt actually shared this
article where he went through how he
created this game and he's calling it
the gauntlet loop. And since then,
people have used that gauntlet loop
prompting technique to recreate that
same level of build quality. So, to show
a few examples, here's one where he
recreated the starting area for Pokémon
in Perfect 3D. Here is an example for a
car racing simulator game. And this is
one where it's more of like a Mario Kart
type of game. And this is just crazy how
wellbuilt this looks. Like, you can see
the different textures of this
environment, like with the road, the
houses there. And there's just so much
detail that the AI model was able to
build out in this one game. And you
might not be into game development in
particular. And later on, we'll show
some use cases of how you can apply this
outside of just video games. But
personally, I still like to pay
attention to these demos because it just
points to how much raw capability these
AI models now have. And Andre Karpati
was able to probably articulate it
better than I can where last weekend he
made this post where he's saying that
we're starting to leave the territory
where you would test an LLM by creating
an SVG of a pelican on a bicycle, which
is this old test that AI models were
used to be run on. And he mentions here
that these kinds of examples are great
because no one in their right mind would
ever spend the time to write something
this custom. But LMS and AI models have
all the stamina and patience in the
world. So these hyper custom worlds and
3D environments are a really great
example of new capabilities that you
yourself as an AI user are now able to
tap into that you couldn't really do
before. So what is the gauntlet loop
exactly? Well, thankfully Matt also
shared his exact prompt here. And
surprisingly it is quite simple. It is
only a threeline prompt. And so you can
see I just pasted that whole prompt in
here. And what's actually more
interesting here versus the actual
verbiage of this prompt is just the
pattern and structure of it. Because if
you really break this down into these
three lines, essentially what you have
is a prompt structure that you can copy
yourself where first you give it a task
of what you want to happen. In this
case, the task that Matt was going for
is to build a firsterson shooter game.
And then the second part here is
essentially the build method. to how
that agent is going to achieve that task
where he's asking the main agent to fan
out sub agents and have each of those
tackle each task individually and to
have a separate sub agent check it
visually to ensure that it looks really
really good. And then finally, the third
part to this is the bar to hit, which is
essentially the standard where the agent
can decide when it can stop. And so he's
saying here to not stop until each sub
agent is utterly wowed with the quality
when compared with the actual Call of
Duty game. And what actually makes this
gauntlet loop so effective are these two
parts right here. Because if you haven't
tried using sub agents to orchestrate
your work before, then this might just
be one of the easiest and quickest way
for you to try it out. But just to step
back in case you don't know what we're
referring to when we talk about sub
agent orchestration. Essentially, when
you prompt an agent or talk to an AI
model, there's three levels to it. At
least in how I think about it. The first
level, which is the most basic and
probably the most common, is when you do
work with an agent, you send a prompt.
It provides an output back to you. You
verify if that output already matches
your standard and then you send another
prompt until you get to what you want.
But it turns out this role of being the
verifier can actually be offloaded to an
agent as well. And so this concept of
loops came about where if you take this
to the next level, you can actually have
an agent work for you and the agent also
does the verification. And so this agent
right here will assume the role of a
critic and you'll just have these two AI
agents talk to each other until it meets
a certain standard, a bar that you set.
And only then will this critic agent
actually pass to you the final output.
And by the way, this whole idea of
having a verifier agent in order to
increase quality output is not new at
all. In fact, this is an article by
Entropic called building effective
agents. And as a part of their study,
they're mentioning here that same
finding that they have where if you have
an AI model generate the output. They
actually find that you generally get
better outputs if you have another AI
model assume the role of an evaluator.
And this is probably not surprising
because if you think about how AI models
usually behave, they usually convince
themselves that the output that they
generate is already good enough. And so
it turns out that having another model
just validate that is actually good
practice. And mind you, this was an
article from way back in 2024. So the
concept of looping isn't really new. But
what is newer and what this gauntlet
loop has pretty much taken to the
extreme level is that in the build
method of that prompt is actually
instructing the main agent, the one that
you are talking to, to orchestrate and
fan out to a fleet of sub agents with
each of them having a critic partner in
order to just make sure that the parts
that they are creating are up to spec to
the standard that you set before the
final output comes to you. And this is
just a nice way to actually visualize
what's really happening under the hood.
But the great news about the tools that
we have now like claude code is that for
you to do something like this, you don't
actually need to learn any extra
technical tooling. All you need to do is
to have a well ststructured prompt like
this where you're instructing the main
agent to fan out sub agents to have each
of them tackle a task individually and
to have a separate sub agent check their
work in order to meet this bar that you
set. And so if you dissect this gauntlet
loop prompt, then I think that pattern
is the one that's most important to
learn here because there's really no
reason for you to not adopt the same
pattern across any of your builds. And
so obviously I needed to try out this
gauntlet loop prompt structure as well.
And I actually wanted to try it in use
cases beyond just games. And by the way,
if you want to learn how to build and
sell AI systems that businesses actually
pay for, then that's pretty much all we
do over at the Robbernuggets community,
where not only do you get access to the
Claude Living Master Class, which we
update every week and takes you from
zero to mastery with the latest on AI,
but you also get access to our agents as
a service course, which walks you
through how to actually get paid for all
these AI skills that you are learning.
You also get to be part of a genuinely
great community of AI builders. In fact,
you can see just some of the recent wins
our members are getting from the program
right here. So, if you want to start
earning from AI, then check that just in
the pin comment below. Now, back to the
video. And I think if this prompt is
really good at virtual 3D environments,
then just a few months down the road as
these models become even more capable,
then this will probably have a huge
impact on sectors like architecture or
even real estate. And so, the test that
I put out for Opus 5 here is that I gave
it this floor layout of a real real
estate listing at Darling Point here in
Sydney. And I also gave it some
reference photos to match against. So,
there's the living room, there's the
bedroom, and so on. And then for the
prompt itself, if you read through this,
you can notice that it is the same
structure as the gauntlet loop prompt
where we have a task here at the top.
We're saying here that we want Claude to
build an explorable 3D walkthrough of
this apartment. We're giving it the
build method where we want the goal to
be broken down into the smallest pieces
and to fan out sub agents. And we're
giving it that bar to hit where we won't
stop until each critic is utterly wowed.
So each sub aent will need to verify
that that bar has been met. And this
whole prompt, I didn't write it myself,
by the way. Near the end, I'll share
with you a skill so that whatever task
that you need, you can just instantly
build a gaunt to the loop prompt similar
to this. And when I send that prompt
over, you can see that it created a plan
here where it has these room builder sub
agent and their corresponding partners,
which are these blind critics. And at
least with a Claude desktop app, what's
great about it is that you can actually
view these dynamic workflows now as well
where you can clearly see the phases
that Claude has planned where right now
it's working on the lighting and then
the rooms and then there is a phase
where those sub agents will evaluate
those rooms and it will continue to loop
up until that original bar that we've
set has been satisfied. All right, so it
ran for around 2 hours now and it's
still working. But I think it's already
at a point where we can just showcase
the strength of this prompt because if
you can see here, this whole report,
this HTML page uh Claw just created for
us in order to give us updates of what
it's seeing versus its original peg. So
you can see this left one is the actual
photo that we gave it. And this one on
the right is the screenshots that it
took of that 3D world. And it's already
looking pretty close. Like the kitchen
counter here, this is the original and
this is the one that it created for us.
And even if it's already pretty close,
it's actually still not satisfied. So
you can see that this particular round,
it's still marking as failed and and
it's actually still iterating and
improving the look of this visual. And
so you can see that's where the
importance of setting a really high bar
is because if you actually want this to
be really perfect and you want to run
this for a couple of hours in order to
get a showcase build, then that's
something that you can just let Claude
do for you. But since I don't want to
sit around here waiting for a few hours
more just to complete this 3D app, let's
actually just view what it created for
us here. And there you go. You can see
we are in this living area. It even
captured the painting for us. Obviously,
the couches are not perfect yet, but I
think if we go around here, we can see
the kitchen counter. It has that marble
finish. And remember, this whole thing
was oneshotted by Claude using that
gauntlet loop prompt that we gave it.
And just to show a sample view. So, this
is the kitchen counter. And this was the
original peg that we gave to Claude. So,
it's pretty close, right? Then if we go
to the bedroom, obviously this texture
probably can be improved in later
passes, but I think it was able to
capture at least the look and the size
of the layout of the photo. And again,
just for reference, these are the images
that we fed to Opus 5. So that's pretty
close, at least in terms of the layout.
And then this is the other bedroom,
which for reference, this is the image
that we fed it. And probably if we gave
it a bit more time, it'll probably be
able to improve the textures of these
some more. But that's just a quick demo
of how you can use the gauntlet loop.
Now, apart from 3D worlds and 3D
environments, what I also did is to just
test out this gauntlet loop prompting
structure to create a front-end website
designed for this ketone IQ product. And
when we launched this workflow, you can
see it ran for around an hour and 19
minutes. And it's the same thing where
it fanned out several sub agents in
order to create our website and also
have this judging phase which is
essentially that evaluator agents to
check the worker agents builds. And what
it created for us is this. So let me
just shift that so you can see. So we
have the product here. We have brain
fuel as the headline. We have a dark
mode and a light mode. And if we scroll
down, we have these nice animations that
just provide you some more details about
this product. And I think what Opus did
here is it actually fanned out some
research agents in order to just make
sure that these numbers are correct.
Now, this is pretty good if you're just
looking at the visual flare of it
because obviously this is quite far
already from the normal AI vibecoded
designs that you may be used to or see.
However, even though this looks pretty
good, remember that visual flare is not
really the only thing that brands or
clients look for, especially when it
comes to these websites. Because if we
to look at Ketone IQ's actual website,
their brand design system is actually
quite different. So, I think the
gauntlet loop can still help you out
quite a lot, but if you don't start with
a really good minimum viable design or
product, then what the gauntlet loop
will do is just optimize towards
probably the wrong thing. And this is
really important to consider, especially
with powerful prompt structures like
these. Because if you notice those
gauntlet loop prompt that we ran, in
fact, any looping prompt that you run,
they usually take a lot of time and
tokens for them to finish. And so the
way that I would use them moving forward
personally is probably not to start with
them as your initial prompt. Because
what can happen there is even though the
final output that you would get looks
good, they might not actually be on
brief and might be really far from what
you want because you just let the agent
decide the direction for you. But if you
start with a really strong minimum
viable product or in this case a design
system which I've taught in previous
other tutorials in this channel and in
our community then you can just
introduce this gauntlet loop prompt as
sort of a warp drive in terms of just
sharpening or polishing the quality of
that MVP so that the version two of the
build that you're making not only looks
good but it is also sitting on a good
foundation and is on brief. And as
mentioned, if you want to try out this
gauntlet loop prompting for yourself,
what I've done is to build out this
skill called slashgauntlet loop. And
what this skill does is whenever you use
it, you can just give a particular task
and it will create a gauntlet loop
prompt for you. And you can just grab
this down in the description below. But
there, I hope that was useful and
informative. And as always, thanks for
watching until the end if you made it
this far. I'll see you next time.
Cheers. [music]